This is the under side of the deck.
Most decks aren't coated underneath.
Some people say that the wood should breathe.
Others think it should be sealed tight.
I personally don't lean one way or the other.
If you have your deck over a patio or your driveway or carport you probably want to have it painted.
So this is raw wood.
It has been here 20 years.
It has just grayed from the tannins in the redwood and everything.
Where there are water marks on the deck if you paint this a light color you will have to coat it 3, 4, 10 times to get rid of water marks because they just bleed through and bleed through.
They were using the charcoal colored stain on the top and I believe it would cover these boards up in one coat really good.
So that leaves you something to think about if you want to coat the bottom of your deck or not.
Also you don't think it is that much area, maybe as much as the top of the deck but with all these joists so you almost have to double what you think you're going to need to paint the bottom of a deck.
It will go very very quickly.
Now when I do the underside of a deck I use my air sprayer.
I have it turned up a little bit higher.
I shoot it and I leave it.
I don't try to get in there with a pad and pad it out and everything.
I just hit it as best I can with one good coat and make sure there are not any drips or runs in it and let it set and that should take care of it.